50 years after we last left footprints on the Moon,
NASA's Artemis I
is our first bold step towards getting us back there
and pushing us farther
than we've ever been before.
You are looking at the world's
most powerful rocket and Orion
spacecraft live on Launch Pad 39B .
The energy here is palpable
as we attempt to make history today.
We're going to learn so much
about the solar system
from the Moon and even about the Earth.
Range weather -
weather is go for launch.
The mission management team has been told
you have a go to proceed
with terminal count.
On behalf of all the men and women
across our great nation who have worked
to bring this hardware together
to make this day possible.
At this time, I give you a go to resume
count and launch Artemis I.
Four stage engine start.
Three, two, one.
Boosters and ignition!
And liftoff of Artemis I!
We rise together back to the Moon
and beyond!
[cheering]
SLS now traveling 607 miles per hour.
The harder the climb, the better the view.
We showed the Space Coast tonight.
What a beautiful view it is.
The first step
in returning our country to the Moon
and on to Mars.
We are understanding now from the
James Webb Space Telescope
just how big and vast this universe is.
There's a lot out there to explore
and this is the next beginning.
Orion is now flying free.
Attached to the European Service Module
and on its journey to the Moon.
Through Artemis missions, NASA will land the first woman
and the first person of color on the Moon
Paving the way for long-term lunar presence
Using innovative technologies to explore more
of the lunar surface than ever before
and serving as a steppingstone to send
astronauts to Mars